Guide to the McGraw-Hill Marketing Information Center Vertical File, 1948-1991
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
- Advertising Series (ADV), 23 Boxes
  - ADV 55. ADVERTISING VOLUME, Expenditures in Major Media (Box 44)
    - ADV 55:3 Multi-Media Expenditures
      - 55:3-1 Advertising Age: forecasts and historical statistics, as prepared by Robert J. Coen
        To quote Ad Age, over the years, Robert J. Coen, senior Vice-President of McCann-Erickson, has become generally recognized as the 'official' keeper of the records concerning advertising expenditures, as well as the prognosticator of the future. Prior to writing for Ad Age, Mr. Coen published his compilations and analyses in the discontinued Printers' Ink which subsequently became Marketing/Communications now, too, defunct. Mr. Coen continued the pioneering work of the late Dr. L.D.H. Weld, Director of Research, McCann-Erickson, Inc., whose ad volume statistics appeared for many years in Printers' Ink. Coen/Weld expenditure data by medium are available back to the mid-1930s as a matter of course; earlier Weld by-medium statistics - which the MIC has on file - date back to at least 1928 and his total volume of advertising figures date back to 1867. It is interesting to compare the Coen-developed expenditure figures with those developed by Charles Yang and others and published in Advertising Age from 1965 through 1971 - see next subsection.
        - 55:3-1.1 Advertising Age: Estimated Annual Expenditures, compiled by Charles Yang and others.
          This historic series featured in Ad Age during the period 1965 through 1971 is interesting in that Mr. Yang used the input-output concept as the basis for his estimates; at the time of first publication, Ad Age claimed that the Yang estimates based on solid government figures ... show a more consistent pattern of advertising growth ... than those developed for Printers' Ink by McCann-Erickson ... See preceding subsection; the MIC has the complete series
        - 55:3-1.2 Advertising Age: 100 Leaders, Expenditures by Medium; by year
      - 55:3-2 Doyle Dane Bernbach: Media Trends (annual report intended to provide a reference for media developments; trends shown for national and local/retail advertising expenditures, costs [rates], audience, CPM and other measurements unique to each medium) (Box 45)
      - 55:3-3 Leading National Advertisers, Inc. (LNA)
        LNA features a complete reporting of advertising expenditures in six major media: consumer magazines, newspaper supplements, network television, spot television, network radio, and outdoor.
        - 55:3-3.1 Company/Brand $ (companies listed alphabetically showing company totals and ad expenditures for their brands in each medium)
        - 55:3-3.2 Ad $ Summary (brands listed alphabetically showing total 6-media expenditures and media used, parent company, subsidiary and class identification)
        - 55:3-3.3 Class/Brand Quarterly (brands grouped within each of LNA's 240-plus product classes showing brand expenditures in each medium for current quarter data)
        - 55:3-3.4 Class/Brand Year-to-Date (brands grouped within each of LNA's 240-plus product classes showing brand expenditures in each medium for year-to-date data)
      - 55:3-4 Media/Scope (discontinued) National Advertising Expenditures Index (historic examples only)
      - 55:3-5 Printers' Ink - Marketing/Communications (discontinued): selected examples of historic studies
        - 55:3-5.1 How the Big 25 Advertised; Barbour Walker Lyndon study of the media choices of 25 advertisers during a fourteen-year period (1936-1949)
        - 55:3-5.2 Leading Advertisers of (year) and Their Expenditures; Barbour Walker Lyndon studies based on PIB figures, 1928-1946
        - 55:3-5.3 Million Dollar Advertisers; Barbour Walker Lyndon studies in various forms
        - 55:3-5.4 M/C's National Advertising Index
        - 55:3-5.5 One Hundred Top Advertisers in (year); Barbour Walker Lyndon studies
      - 55:3-6 Public Relations Journal: The Cost of Corporate Advertising in year annual survey of corporate advertising spending, by medium
      - 55:3-7 Tide (discontinued)
        - 55:3-7.1 Advertising Index (historic examples)
        - 55:3-7.2 Survey of Media Buying Trends (historic example)
    - ADV 55:4 Miscellaneous Intelligence on Advertising Volume, N.E.C.
      - 55:4-1 Printers' Ink (discontinued); historic studies showing expenditure practices of typical national advertisers in so-called unmeasured media
      - 55:4-2 Number of Ads Seen Daily
      - 55:4-3 Reference Sources for Advertising Volume Information
- International Operations Series (IOP), 9 Boxes
  The headings featured in this section tie in very closely with those to be found in the Administration, Advertising and Marketing sections of the Index. They are, really, international derivatives of domestic management and marketing topics; therefore, they should ALWAYS be used in conjunction with the headings to be found in ADM, ADV, MKT and SAL.
  To the eye of the professional international marketer the headings may seem a bit cursory; however, the MIC each year receives only a relatively small handful of questions relating to international management/marketing subjects and the paucity of international headings reflects the noticeable lack of questions on the overall topic.
  - IOP 0. ECONOMIC ENVIRONMENT (Box 46)
    - IOP 0:1 The International Financial/Monetary System, N.E.C.
      - 0:1-1 Balance of Payments
      - 0:1-2 Eurodollars
      - 0:1-3 Petrodollars
    - IOP 0:2 America's Stake in International Trade, N.E.C.
      - 0:2-1 Patterns and Problems in U.S. Investments Overseas, N.E.C.
      - 0:2-2 McGraw-Hill Department of Economics series: Overseas Operations of U.S. Industrial Companies
      - 0:2-3 Foreign (including foreign media) Investment in the U.S.
        See also: IOP 0:4, Tariffs and Trade Policies: Imports
    - IOP 0:3 Regional Trade Groupings: Commentary, N.E.C. (e.g. Common Market Implications for U.S.) (Box 47)
      See also: IOP 10:4, Trading Markets, and Marketing by Continent and Country, selected subsections
      - 0:3-1 ANCOM (Andean Common Market)
      - 0:3-2 Arab Economic Unity Agreement
      - 0:3-3 ASEAN (Association of South East Asian Nations)
      - 0:3-4 Benelux
      - 0:3-5 CACM (Central American Common Market)
      - 0:3-6 CARIFTA (Caribbean Free Trade Area)
      - 0:3-7 CMEA (COMECON) (Council for Mutual Economic Assistance)
      - 0:3-8 East African Community
      - 0:3-9 EEC (European Economic Community)
      - 0:3-10 EFTA (European Free Trade Association)
      - 0:3-11 LAFTA (ALALC) (Latin American Free Trade Association)
      - 0:3-12 NAFTA (North American Free Trade Area)
      - 0:3-13 NORDEK (The Nordic Council)
      - 0:3-14 OCAM (Organization Commune Africaine et Malgache)
      - 0:3-15 Other Regional Groupings, N.E.C.
    - IOP 0:4 Tariffs and Trade Policies: Imports (includes information for those exporting to the United States)
    - IOP 0:5 Trade Zones
    - IOP 0:6 World Business/Economic Forecasts and Reviews, N.E.C.
      - 0:6-1 McGraw-Hill Department of Economics World Business Outlook series (discontinued)
      - 0:6-2 The New York Times Annual International Economic Review (discontinued)
      - 0:6-3 International Economic Indicators, N.E.C. (Box 48)
        - 0:6-3.1 Business International's Annual Indicators of Market Size
    - IOP 0:7 World Industry: Rankings of Top Companies, N.E.C.
      See also: ADM 0:2-4.14, Rankings of U.S. Corporations, all subsections
      - 0:7-1 Business Week: surveys of international corporate performance
      - 0:7-2 Fortune: Largest Industrials Outside the U.S. (includes variations similar to this series; for example, The Largest Industrial Companies in the World)
      - 0:7-3 President Magazine: President Directory (Japan)
      - 0:7-4 Ward's Leading Worldwide Corporations
  - IOP 5. FUNDAMENTALS OF INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS
    - IOP 5:1 Organizing for International Business, N.E.C. (frameworks and guidelines for structuring international and multinational operations: analyzing foreign opportunities)
      See also: ADM 0, CORPORATE ORGANIZATION, all subsections; IOP 10, INTERNATIONAL MARKETING/EXPORTING, selected subsections; IOP 5:2, Multinational Corporations, selected subsections; IOP 5:5, International Law, all subsections
      - 5:1-1 Foreign Divestment
      - 5:1-2 Joint Ventures Overseas
      - 5:1-3 Plant Site Selection
      - 5:1-4 Selecting Overseas Representatives
    - IOP 5:2 Multinational Corporations: Their Place in World Markets: Problems, Profiles - including Forbes' listing of 100 Largest U.S. MNCs - and Prospects in Combination and/or N.E.C. (the evolution of MNCs)
    - IOP 5:2 Multinational Corporations: Their Place in World Markets: Problems, Profiles - including Forbes' listing of 100 Largest U.S. MNCs - and Prospects in Combination and/or N.E.C. (the evolution of MNCs) (Box 49)
      See also: IOP 5:1, Organizing for International Business, N.E.C.; IOP 0:2-1, Patterns and Problems in U.S. Investments Overseas, N.E.C. for information on MNCs' Investments Overseas; IOP 10:4, Trading Markets by Country, for MNC effects on specific areas or countries; IOP 5:6, International (comparative) Management, selected subsections for information on specific MNC management topics, e.g. the MNC financial function; also other specific topics wherever MNCs might be involved.
      - 5:2-1 MNCs' Impact on International Marketing
      - 5:2-2 MNC Controversies, N.E.C.
        - 5:2-2.1 MNC/Host Country Relations (includes problems of foreign MNCs operating in the U.S.)
        - 5:2-2.2 MNC/MN Union Challenges
        - 5:2-2.3 MNCs and the LDCs
          See also: IOP 10:4, Third World or LDC countries, marketing references
        - 5:2-2.4 Rejoinders to Such Claims as: MNCs Rob Domestic Workers of Jobs and Adversely Affect the Balance of Payments Position
        - 5:2-2.5 Social Role of the MNCs
        - 5:2-2.6 Technology Transfer, International
    - IOP 5:3 Financial Aspects of Overseas Operations, N.E.C.
      - 5:3-1 Evaluating Profitability (ROI) of Overseas Operations
      - 5:3-2 Interpretation of Overseas Financial Operations (reporting foreign operations)
      - 5:3-3 Overseas Production Costs
        See also: IOP 5:6-3, International Management, Experiences with Overseas Work Forces
      - 5:3-4 Raising Capital for Overseas Operations (includes information on agencies that help finance foreign trade)
      - 5:3-5 Unusual Overseas Payments (corporate corruption)
        See also: IOP 10:3-3, Cultural Analysis
    - IOP 5:4 Foreign Competition
      See also: IOP 5:2-2.6, Technology Transfer; IOP 0:2-3, Foreign Investment in the U.S.
    - IOP 5:5 International Law
      See also: specific subjects throughout IOP classifications for information on law as it applies to particular topics; for example, IOP 5:1-2, Joint Ventures Overseas for legal problems in the venturing process
      - 5:5-1 Legal Perspective, N.E.C. (information on international tax relations, tax havens, guides to restrictive business practices, etc.)
        See also: ADV 25, DECEPTION, ETHICS, TRUTH AND TASTE IN ADVERTISING, selected subsections; MKT 35, LEGAL ASPECTS OF MARKETING, selected subsections
      - 5:5-2 Industrial Property Rights (copyrights, patents, trademarks, etc.
        See also: ADM 0:2-10, Public Affairs/Relations, sections on Copyrights, Logos, Slogans, Trade Characters/Names and Marks, Corporate; Patents and Patenting
      - 5:5-3 Overseas Licensing/International Sales/Marketing Contracts
    - IOP 5:6 International (comparative) Management: Role, Problems and Techniques of the International Manager, N.E.C. (information on international management development and specific international management functions such as international financial management)
    - IOP 5:6 International (comparative) Management: Role, Problems and Techniques of the International Manager, N.E.C. (information on international management development and specific international management functions such as international financial management) (Box 50)
      See also: ADM, ADMINISTRATION, all subsections
      - 5:6-1 Compensation of International Management: Programs, Guidelines, Trends
        See also: IOP 10:3-3, Cultural Analysis; ADM 0:2-8.4, Compensation, Executive/Management, all subsections; ADV 5:10-9, Advertising Agencies, Personnel, Salaries; MKT 40:1-2.1.3, Marketing Communications Management, Statistical Profiles including Compensation; SAL 20:1, 20:2, 20:3, Compensation, sales
      - 5:6-2 Consultants Overseas
        See also: ADM 0:2-7.3, Consultants
      - 5:6-3 Experiences with Overseas Work Forces (managing human resources on the global scale)
      - 5:6-4 Foreign Nationals in International Management
      - 5:6-5 Management in the Developing Countries
  - IOP 10. INTERNATIONAL MARKETING
    See also: MKT, MARKETING, all subsections
    - IOP 10:1 International Marketing/Export Marketing: Organization, Planning and Strategy, N.E.C. (includes Fortune 50 Leading Exporters)
      See also: IOP 5:1, Organizing for International Business, all subsections; IOP 10:3-2.1.1, Sources of Overseas Marketing Information
      - 10:1-1 Comparative Marketing (Box 51)
      - 10:1-2 Integrated Distribution
      - 10:1-3 New Product Introduction Overseas
        - 10:1-3.1 Product Life Cycles in Global Marketing Strategies
          See also: MKT 60:2-2, Product Life Cycles
      - 10:1-4 Standardized Marketing (includes information on Global Marketing)
    - IOP 10:2 International Marketing Communications
      - 10:2-1 Advertising Operations: Practices, Problems, Principles, Procedures and Strategies for U.S. Firms Selling Overseas, N.E.C. (advertising from an international point of view)
        See also: ADV, ADVERTISING, all subsections; IOP 10:3-1, Advertising Management
      - 10:2-2 International Communications and the Advertising Industry in: by country within each defined continent or area as follows:
        - 10:2-2.1 Africa, N.E.C.
        - 10:2-2.2 America, Central, N.E.C.
        - 10:2-2.3 America, North, N.E.C.
        - 10:2-2.4 America, South, N.E.C.
          - 10:2-2.4.1 Latin America advertising references
        - 10:2-2.5 Asia, N.E.C.
          - 10:2-2.5.1 Middle East advertising references
        - 10:2-2.6 Australia/New Zealand
        - 10:2-2.7 Europe, East
        - 10:2-2.8 Europe, West
        - 10:2-2.9 Third World or Less Developed Country (LDC) advertising references
          These files should always be used in conjunction with IOP 10:2-7, selected subsections
      - 10:2-3 Global Challenges to Advertising
        See also: ADV 15, ATTITUDES TOWARDS ADVERTISING, all subsections; ADV 25, DECEPTION, ETHICS, TRUTH AND TASTE IN ADVERTISING, all subsections; ADV 30, LEGAL ASPECTS OF ADVERTISING; MKT 35, LEGAL ASPECTS OF MARKETING, all subsections particularly MKT 35:3, Consumerism
      - 10:2-4 International Advertising Concepts and Techniques, N.E.C.
        - 10:2-4.1 Centralization (centrally-developed advertising campaigns)
        - 10:2-4.2 Decentralization (local - including co-op advertising)
        - 10:2-4.3 Standardization and/or Transference
          See also: IOP 10:1-4, Standardized Marketing
      - 10:2-5 International Copy Techniques, N.E.C.
        See also: ADV 50:4, Copy Approaches and Themes, all subsections
        - 10:2-5.1 Corporate Messages in International Advertising, N.E.C.
          See also: ADV 50:4-3.9, Copy Approaches and Themes, Corporate Image
        - 10:2-5.2 Copy Translation and Writing Problems
          See also: IOP 10:3-3, Cultural Analysis; IOP 10:4, Trading Markets, Marketing in, and Marketing Research by Country, for problems which might arise in specific countries or areas of the world
      - 10:2-6 International Advertising Agencies, N.E.C.
        See also: ADV 5, ADVERTISING AGENCIES, all subsections
        - 10:2-6.1 Advertising Age Annual Compilations: foreign agency income reports and profiles
        - 10:2-6.2 American Association of Advertising Agencies, Inc., Directories of The Advertising Agency Business Around The World (historic)
        - 10:2-6.3 Advertising World's Annual Review of International Agency Billings from the U.S.
        - 10:2-6.4 Other Compilations of Overseas Ad Agency Billing Statistics
      - 10:2-7 International Advertising Media
        See also: ADV 35, MEDIA, all subsections
        - 10:2-7.1 International Advertising Media, N.E.C. (role, flavor and kinds of media available overseas to the American marketer)
        - 10:2-7.2 Business Papers Overseas, N.E.C.
          See also: ADV 35:1, Media, Business Papers, all subsections. See IOP 10:2-7.5 for material covering business papers and mass media in combination.
          Information filed by country within each defined continent or area as follows:
          - 10:2-7.2.1 Africa, N.E.C.
          - 10:2-7.2.2 America, Central, N.E.C.
          - 10:2-7.2.3 America, North, N.E.C.
          - 10:2-7.2.4 America, South, N.E.C.
            - 10:2-7.2.4.1 Latin America business paper references
          - 10:2-7.2.5 Asia, N.E.C. (Box 52)
            - 10:2-7.2.5.1 Middle East business paper references
          - 10:2-7.2.6 Australia/New Zealand
          - 10:2-7.2.7 Europe, East, N.E.C.
          - 10:2-7.2.8 Europe, West, N.E.C.
          - 10:2-7.2.9 Third World or Less Developed Country (LDC) business paper references
        - 10:2-7.3 Catalogs
          See also: ADV 35:2, Catalogs, all subsections
        - 10:2-7.4 Direct Mail/Mail Marketing/Direct Response Advertising
          See also: ADV 35:3, Direct Mail, all subsections
        - 10:2-7.5 Mass Media (general magazines, cinema, TV, posters, etc., individually or in combination)
          Information filed by country within each continent or area as follows:
          - 10:2-7.5.1 Africa, N.E.C.
          - 10:2-7.5.2 America, Central, N.E.C.
          - 10:2-7.5.3 America, North, N.E.C.
          - 10:2-7.5.4 America, South, N.E.C.
            - 10:2-7.5.4.1 Latin America mass media references
          - 10:2-7.5.5 Asia, N.E.C.
            - 10:2-7.5.5.1 Middle East mass media references
          - 10:2-7.5.6 Australia/New Zealand
          - 10:2-7.5.7 Europe, East, N.E.C.
          - 10:2-7.5.8 Europe, West, N.E.C.
          - 10:2-7.5.9 Third World or Less Developed Country (LDC) mass media references
      - 10:2-8 Media Buying, Planning and Selection in International Marketing, N.E.C.
        See also: IOP 10:2-2, International Communications and the Advertising Industry in: selected subsections; ADV 50:5, Media Buying, Evaluation and Selection, all subsections
        - 10:2-8.1 Checklists for International Media Buying and Planning
        - 10:2-8.2 Media Buying, Planning and Selection
          Arranged by country within each continent or area as follows:
          - 10:2-8.2.1 Africa, N.E.C.
          - 10:2-8.2.2 America, Central, N.E.C.
          - 10:2-8.2.3 America, North, N.E.C.
          - 10:2-8.2.4 America, South, N.E.C.
            - 10:2-8.2.4.1 Latin America buying, planning and selection references
          - 10:2-8.2.5 Asia, N.E.C.
            - 10:2-8.2.5.1 Middle East buying, planning and selection references
          - 10:2-8.2.6 Australia/New Zealand
          - 10:2-8.2.7 Europe, East, N.E.C.
          - 10:2-8.2.8 Europe, West, N.E.C.
          - 10:2-8.2.9 Third World or Less Developed Country (LDC) buying, planning and selection references
      - 10:2-9 International Circulation Auditing and Audience Measurement
        See also: ADV 50:5-4.2, Circulation (Audience/Universe/Total Audience) Measurement and Research Concepts, all subsections; ADV 50:5-4.3, Circulation (Audience/Universe): Auditing Bureaus, all subsections; ADV 50:5-4.4, Circulation (Audience/Universe): Auditing Bureaus Around the World
      - 10:2-10 World Advertising Expenditures
        - 10:2-10.1 Starch INRA Hooper/IAA Compilations and Commentary
        - 10:2-10.2 World Advertising Expenditures, N.E.C. (individual country or regional statistics other than U.S.; for U.S. expenditures see ADV 55, ADVERTISING VOLUME: EXPENDITURES IN MAJOR MEDIA, selected subsections)
      - 10:2-11 Exhibiting Overseas, N.E.C.
        See also: MKT 25, EXHIBITS AND SHOWS, selected subsections
        - 10:2-11.1 Trade Fairs
        - 10:2-11.2 Trade Missions
      - 10:2-12 Public Relations as an Overseas Marketing Tool
        See also: ADM 0:2-10, Public Affairs/Relations all subsections
      - 10:2-13 Sales Promotion Overseas
        See also: MKT 40:1-7, Sales Promotion Management; SAL 30, SALES PROMOTION, all subsections
    - IOP 10:3 International Marketing Management, N.E.C.
      See also: MKT 40, MARKETING/COMMUNICATIONS ADMINISTRATION, all subsections
      - 10:3-1 International Advertising Management: Controlling the Overseas Advertising Operation
        See also: MKT 40:1-2.1, Advertising Management, selected subsections; ADV 10, ADVERTISING APPROPRIATIONS, all subsections
      - 10:3-2 International Marketing Research Management
        See also: MKT 40:1-5, Market Research Management, and subsection
        - 10:3-2.1 International Marketing and Information Research Techniques, N.E.C.
          See also: IOP 10:4, Trading Markets, Marketing in, and Marketing Research, by Country and/or Continent, selected subsections for research techniques applicable to specified geographic areas; MKT 50, MARKETING RESEARCH, all subsections
          - 10:3-2.1.1 Sources of Overseas Marketing Information, N.E.C.
            See also: specific IOP classifications; for example: IOP 5:3-4, Raising Capital for Overseas Operations, for information on sources that aid in financing overseas trade; MKT 50:7, Sources of Information
      - 10:3-3 Cultural Analysis: commentary on such topics as cultural shock and reverse cultural shock, getting along with local communities and businessmen, prices/earnings around the globe, business etiquette overseas, internatonal terrorism, business customs abroad (Box 53)
        See also: IOP 10:4, Trading Markets, and Marketing, by Country and/or Continent, selected subsections for information on allied topics on a by country or by area basis; IOP 5:3-5, Unusual Overseas Payments
    - IOP 10:4 Trading Markets, Marketing in, Marketing Research and Economic Conditions by Country and/or Continent/Region
      - 10:4-1 Africa, N.E.C.
      - 10:4-2 America, Central, N.E.C.
      - 10:4-3 America, North, N.E.C.
      - 10:4-4 America, South, N.E.C.
        - 10:4-4.1 Latin America marketing references
      - 10:4-5 Asia, N.E.C.
        - 10:4-5.1 Middle East marketing references
      - 10:4-6 Australia/New Zealand (Box 54)
      - 10:4-7 Europe, East, N.E.C.
      - 10:4-8 Europe, West, N.E.C.
      - 10:4-9 Third World or Less Developed Country (LDC) marketing references
      - 10:4-10 International Trading Markets in Combination or N.E.C.
    - IOP 10:5 Trade Associations Overseas
      See also: MKT 80, TRADE ASSOCIATIONS; IOP 10:3-2.1.1, Sources of Overseas Marketing Information
- Marketing Series (MKT), 20 Boxes
  No headings are provided in this section for the so-called standard marketing research reference works to be found in any business library. Such reference works would include: the U.S. Census of Manufactures; the U.S. Annual Survey of Manufactures; the Current Industrial Reports; the U.S. Industrial Outlook; County Business Patterns; the Bureau of the Census Catalog; the Directory of Federal Statistics for Local Areas, a Guide to Services; Predicast's F&S Index; The Wall Street Transcript; S&P's Register of Corporations; Directors and Executives; S&P's Industry Surveys; Moody's Industrial Manual ... ad infinitum.